# social_studies_quiz.py
questions = [
    {
        "question": "_________ is a building in which people live that has several rooms for varied purposes.",
        "options": ["A. Market", "B. House", "C. Mall"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "All these are materials required in house construction except",
        "options": ["A. Iron roofing sheet", "B. Bricks", "C. Sculpture"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "People living in _______ settle have better access to social amenities.",
        "options": ["A. Rural", "B. Urban", "C. Underwood"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Psychological effects of drug abuse include",
        "options": ["A. Stealing", "B. Restlessness", "C. Fraud"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these promotes physical hygiene?",
        "options": ["A. Regular exercise", "B. Inadequate meal", "C. Accident"],
        "answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of these is not a consequence of absence of moral responsibilities?",
        "options": ["A. Respect & honesty", "B. Indiscipline", "C. Abnormal behavior"],
        "answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "___________Pollution means air containing harmful substances dangerous to life.",
        "options": ["A. Water", "B. Air", "C. Land"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not an example of a natural disaster?",
        "options": ["A. Cyclone", "B. Blizzards", "C. Chemical accidents"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "Unpleasant things which happen unexpectedly are referred to as",
        "options": ["A. Disaster", "B. Strangling", "C. Jazz"],
        "answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the differences between man and woman is",
        "options": ["A. Talk", "B. Pregnancy", "C. Eating"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "One of the factors that can hinder growth in children is",
        "options": ["A. Cleanliness", "B. Inadequate diet", "C. Personal hygiene"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "All these are effects of abuse of stimulants except",
        "options": ["A. Restlessness", "B. Sleepiness", "C. Excellent work performance"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "There are ___________ geopolitical zones in Nigeria.",
        "options": ["A. 3", "B. 5", "C. 6"],
        "answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "question": "_________ means working or acting together to achieve a particular aim.",
        "options": ["A. Organization", "B. Cooperation", "C. Politics"],
        "answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "question": "A person who wants to develop good saving habits must not be",
        "options": ["A. Prudent", "B. Extravagant", "C. Disciplined"],
        "answer": "B"
    }
]
